I decided to cover both open
problems in deep reinforcement
learning and how to
do deep RL research.
So let's start with part 1 and
talking about open problems
and frontiers in deep
reinforcement learning.
I'm going to break this into
a few different categories.
The first is challenges on
defining the problem setup.
The second is
challenges in methods.
And the third is challenges
in deployment and evaluation.
I should also mention that
this will not be exhaustive.
There's many problems
and many open challenges
in deep reinforcement learning.
I'm just picking out some of the
ones that I think I've either
gotten questions about quite
a bit or some of the problems
that I think are
the most exciting
and the most interesting.
So let's dive in.
And in particular,
in terms of some
of the challenges in how we
set up the deep RL problem,
we've seen a lot of
successes in domains
like games, math, reasoning,
coding problems, where you can
very easily define the reward.
You can very easily
verify whether or not
the reinforcement learning
system did the correct thing,
which is great.
But in many real-world
scenarios, rewards don't exist.
Or rewards are very delayed.
And this introduces challenges
in the typical problem setting.
And so, for example, let's
think about language models
for chatbots.
Right now, we have
preference optimization.
And one might actually say
that preference optimization
for chatbots seems
to work quite well.
We're able to actually deploy
reinforcement learning at scale.
But there's actually
pretty big problems
with preference optimization.
And as one example, there
was this research paper
by Sharma and Tong that
was evaluating what
preferences people are giving.
And the x-axis is
the probability
that a response with
the given feature
is preferred when
all else is equal.
And there's different things
here on the left axis.
And the things that
were most preferred
in the human preferences
were whether it was something
that the human agreed with and
whether or not the response
was confident.
So essentially, the things that
people are giving preferences
for are whether or not the
language model response
is something that's
confidently saying something
and whether that
thing that it's saying
agrees with what
the person thinks.
And then all the way
down here is factuality.
And so they're
actually caring about
whether it's confident more than
whether or not the response is
actually correct or true.
And so people aren't actually
giving good preferences.
Arguably, I think we
would want language models
to be valuing factuality
over things like confidence.
And we're more optimizing
for what people kind of want
to hear rather than the kinds
of responses that will be good.
Now, if you also think about
preference optimization
for personalization,
for example,
we might want to develop
language models that
are telling people
what they want to hear
and the kinds of
recommendations,
for example, that are closely
personalized to their interests
and their beliefs.
But on the flip side,
if we personalize
these kinds of models
for the many people that
use these models,
then it might lead
to polarization in people
who, for example, have
extreme beliefs rather
than being exposed
to a wide range of beliefs.
And so even something
like personalization
may not intrinsically be
what we want to optimize for.
And at the end of
the day, there's
typically multiple things that
we do care about optimizing for.
And balancing those different
objectives that may actually
compete with each
other ends up being
a very challenging problem.
So this whole kind
of realm of how
do we define rewards and
the kind of objective
as a whole for
language models is--
in many ways, there's
a lot of progress.
But it's still a really
challenging problem.
Now, separate from language
models, there's also robotics.
Right now, in
robotics, either you
have binary rewards
in the real world
or, if in simulation, you
might have hand-shaped rewards,
where you define different
terms for what you want.
This takes a lot of effort, ends
up being fairly challenging,
or takes a lot of
labeling annotations.
And even then, even when
you have human annotations,
it can be tricky
to judge rewards.
And so, for example, if you were
to look at these shirts that
were each folded by a robot, if
you were to think about which
shirt was folded the best or try
to give rewards for these shirt
folds, it's rather
tricky to figure out
how you might reward different
mistakes, different amounts
of crinkleness, whether or not
the shirt is off center or not.
It's generally a very ambiguous
problem and hard even for people
to think about how to provide
rewards for these systems.
Another example-- let's think
about YouTube recommendations.
What I mean here is if
when you're on YouTube,
there's recommendations
for a next video
to watch after watching
your current video.
And these an
algorithm that selects
what these
recommendations should be.
Now, we don't have exact details
on how this algorithm works.
But there was a
research paper that
actually was talking
a little bit about how
they do these recommendations.
And as you might expect, when
they do these recommendations,
they want to optimize
for engagement,
which is like whether
or not you actually
clicked on the recommendation.
And if you clicked on
the recommendation,
that was probably a
good recommendation.
And also, satisfaction, which is
that after you clicked on that,
if you actually like
the video, then that's
also a good sign that it
was a good recommendation.
So this all seems reasonable.
But another thing that was
mentioned in the research paper
was that the combination of
these metrics for the reward
function was actually
manually tuned
by a person rather
than something
that is designed automatically.
This kind of also goes
to show the challenge
in actually defining these
kinds of reward functions
when we don't know
how best to balance
these kinds of objectives.
We talked a bit
about math reasoning.
If we want to take
those advances
and apply them to broader
scientific experimentation
and reasoning, you
often don't necessarily
know what the final
answer should be.
And so even training
on math reasoning,
you might see some transfer
to scientific reasoning.
But if you want to
train on a broader
set of scientific
reasoning problems,
this sort of verification
becomes challenging.
And the last thing
I'll mention along
these sorts of rewards
and verification
is that if we think
about how humans learn,
humans often learn by
rolling around on the floor,
playing with random toys.
And it seems like they're
not just optimizing
for one particular task.
They're optimizing--
well, who knows
what they're optimizing for?
For example, we could
develop algorithms
that would allow machines
to explore in this way,
potentially optimizing
for learning, potentially
optimizing for exploration.
And this is certainly
an open problem.
So that's on the problem setup.
Now, let's talk a little
bit about challenges
on the method side.
So the first topic
I wanted to bring up
was leveraging prior
data or knowledge.
So there's a lot
of circumstances
where we're not
starting reinforcement
learning from scratch.
And we have some prior
data, some prior knowledge
about what is best to explore.
And the default tool for
leveraging previous knowledge
and data is to use
pre-trained model weights
or to initialize your replay
buffer with any previous data
that you have.
But this tool doesn't extend
to all sorts of scenarios
we might care about.
There might be
scenarios where we have
more abstract prior knowledge.
Maybe we have some
knowledge that we
read from news articles
that isn't kind
of in the typical data format.
We want to incorporate
those facts into our model.
Maybe we have some
hints that could be
helpful for solving a problem.
And even separate
from that, if we
think about this
kind of paradigm
of using pre-training and
initialized data sets,
there are scenarios
where this might actually
be too constraining.
And so as one example, here's
a research paper by Ball et al.
In 2023.
And they introduced
a method that
was studying using
prior demonstration data
with reinforcement learning.
And the method that
they introduced,
they initialized the buffer.
But they actually didn't
pre-train the weights.
And they found that
pre-training the weights
did worse than not
pre-training the weights.
And so this kind of
suggests that there
might be scenarios where
using pre-trained weights
or using pre-trained data
sets might actually be
too constraining on our model.
As one example of this, if
you have a pre-trained model,
the output layer of
that pre-trained model
might have converged to
something fairly deterministic.
And then if you're trying
to learn something new
or adapt it in a new
way, then that last layer
might not actually be
exploring in a good way.
So that's one example of why
you might see worse performance
if you initialize your weights
with some previous neural
network.
And arguably, in
language models,
perhaps reinforcement
learning works quite well
because pre-trained models often
have a very diverse distribution
over output tokens.
And in terms of leveraging
prior data and knowledge
and also being able
to go beyond it,
I think that this question is
really important for thinking
about how language models can
solve problems that humans
haven't solved
because they probably
should build upon the knowledge
in the pre-trained data sets.
But they also need to think
about how to go beyond that
and not be too constrained by
what the pre-trained model might
say.
And it's also quite
useful for thinking
about how robots or
autonomous vehicles might
learn how to do things
faster and more reliably
than what humans do.
And perhaps if we
constrain too much
to the pre-trained knowledge
or the prior knowledge,
they might not be able to
surpass human abilities in terms
of speed or reliability.
So I think, generally,
these two questions
are really fascinating.
And we've seen some suggestions
that reinforcement learning
can do this.
And it's certainly one of the
most promising tools for going
beyond what humans can do.
But lots of interesting
and open work to do there.
Now, one question I've
gotten quite a bit
is whether we can leverage world
models and video generation
models for robotics and control.
And we've seen some really
impressive results, especially
recently from video
generation models,
where they clearly have a lot of
rich knowledge about the world,
like how cooking on a stove
works, how typing on a keyboard
works, and how that might look
like if the keyboard was made
of gummy bears, and also
how things like even walking
at an abstract level work.
So it seems like this
sort of knowledge
should be really useful
for learning behavior.
But there's actually
a lot of nuance
and a lot of challenges with
using these kinds of models.
As an example, if you train
an action-conditioned video
generation model--
so a model that takes as
input the current image
and future actions and
predicts future video--
and if you train that on
demonstrations and rollouts
from one policy and then
you evaluate a new policy's
actions with that model and
evaluate whether or not that
those actions lead
to good outcomes,
then these actions
won't necessarily
be represented in the data
that the model was trained on.
And as a result, the model often
will make inaccurate predictions
for these actions.
If most of the data
set is demonstrations,
then it will
predict a video that
corresponds to
correctly doing the task
even if these actions did not
lead to a correct outcome.
And generally, these models
have very little data--
for example, like
narrowly making a mistake
or making mistakes that are
very different from the kinds
of mistakes that humans make.
The other thing here is that
even small physical inaccuracies
can lead to poor performance.
And so a lot of times, these
videos look really, really good.
They look like they
might be accurate.
But that doesn't mean that the
underlying physics is actually
accurate.
Now, I think that there
are solutions here.
One possible solution
is to try to train
on data from lots of
different policies
with this kind of
approach, with the hopes
that that will lead to
enough coverage over action
distributions to
leverage these models.
And then the second
possible solution
is that we might be able to
use these video generation
models in other ways.
And one example of
that, maybe instead
of training this sort of
physical model of the future,
we could generate,
for example, what
should the future video look
like not conditioned on actions?
And if we train this
only on demonstrations,
then, for example, we could
predict future video and plan
out how to accomplish the task
in the future in video space
and then run a goal
conditioned policy
using the predicted video.
And something like this kind
of sidesteps the challenge
of this sort of
out-of-distribution action
problem because
you're only using
the model for a form of
planning where you're thinking
through what is a good
outcome in the future
rather than thinking
through what
is the outcome of
specific actions.
And then the third thing
on the method side--
the third challenge
that I'll talk about
is thinking about scaling.
So on the scaling front,
we've seen large-scale RL
succeed with language models.
And that's actually
really exciting to see.
But there's still
shortcomings there.
So a lot of language
model RL is considering
problems that are still fairly
short horizon or extremely
online, like generating
rollouts of the model
every single iteration.
And as an example
of this, if we're
doing preference
optimization, typically we
consider this
single turn dialogue
setting, where we're
getting rewards just
for our next
response rather than
trying to reward the outcome
of the full conversation.
And this means that it's
a shorter horizon problem.
It means you don't have to have
a human in the loop of data
collection to generate those
dialogue conversations.
And so this makes
the problem easier,
which is good to make
the problem easier.
But it means that if there are
scenarios where you have longer
horizon problems or you need
a human in the loop of data
collection, that becomes a
lot more challenging to do
at large scale.
As another example, if
we think about reasoning
for math problems, this
relies on a very large number
of online samples from the model
interleaved with policy updates.
And there are some scenarios
where it's actually really hard
to collect that very online data
interleaved with policy updates,
especially if collecting data
involves interfacing with humans
or interfacing with
the physical world.
So towards this
end, if we wanted
to think about longer
horizon problems
and efficiently learning,
tools like value functions
should be really useful.
We've seen some signs of life
in training value functions
at large scale.
And when using PPO, we train
value functions at large scale.
But these value
functions are primarily
used for reducing
gradient variants
and may not be accurate
enough for doing
a full actor-critic update
or for selecting actions
with a Q-learning
style objective.
And so understanding whether
we can scale that value
function learning and
have value functions
be accurate enough for directly
optimizing policies-- something
that's pretty
interesting to explore
and might be important for
longer horizon problems.
And then second, I mentioned
that very online data collection
can be challenging
at large scale.
And as an example of
this, say that you are--
maybe say that you're like an
autonomous driving company.
You want to do RL.
It's going to be hard to
collect data on all of your cars
at once, then do a policy
update every 30 seconds or even
every minute or even every hour.
It's much easier to first
collect a large batch of data,
like maybe over a couple
of days, maybe over a week,
then update your
policy on all that data
and repeat that process.
And so I refer to that sort of
problem statement as a batch
online setting, where
you're collecting
a batch of online data with one
policy, then doing an update
and repeating.
This more batch data
collection setting
might have challenges
that are a bit
different from your typical
online reinforcement learning
setting.
And so this sort
of data collection
should be quite practical.
You could also do this
potentially asynchronously,
where you're collecting
data asynchronously
from making updates.
And at large scale, this
sort of asynchronous updates
can actually potentially
also be more practical.
And there may be new
considerations on the algorithm
side.
So for example, in one
recent work by Dong et al.,
they found that using
more expressive policies.
Like, diffusion policies
was really, really important
for effective
reinforcement learning
in this batch online setting.
And one explanation for
that is if you're collecting
a large batch of data.
Having diverse
actions be represented
could naturally be
pretty important.
Because in the fully
online setting,
if you have a more
deterministic policy,
if you're going to
be making an update,
maybe it's OK to be more
deterministic because you're
going to change your policy
really, really soon anyway.
And so you'll already
get more diverse data
just from changing your
policy so frequently.
Whereas in the
more batch setting,
you don't have the luxury
of changing your policy so
frequently.
And having a more
diverse distribution
might be quite helpful.
So DPO-- there are algorithms
that are operating much more
offline.
And so there is success there.
The one downside of
that is those problems
are shorter horizon.
And so can we do long horizons
and with less online data?
So yeah, things like
offline RL are also
going to be more
scalable as well.
Let's talk a bit about
deployment and evaluation.
So one problem I think
that is quite important
with these models is
thinking about safety
and how to apply these models
in more safety critical domains.
That could be domains like
medicine, driving, mental health
counseling, legal and
political discourse, and so on.
No shortage of domains
that have challenges
that could lead to safety
critical situations when
you make mistakes.
Now, historically,
this sort of problem
has been approached by
trying to formally verify
the behavior of the model
or provide some sort
of probabilistic guarantees.
But generally,
oftentimes, these methods
are going to make assumptions
that don't hold up
under real-world circumstances.
And so even if you can
verify it in a model,
those verifications often
won't hold at larger scales.
And generally, it's impossible
to fully guarantee safety
in the countless
number of scenarios
that you can encounter
in the real world.
And we find that even
humans make mistakes, even
in safety critical settings.
So human drivers make mistakes,
surgeons, pilots make mistakes,
politicians make
mistakes, and so forth.
So we can't guarantee safety.
But we could at least try to
think about handling safety
critical scenarios effectively.
And arguably, if you were
to think about safety,
there might be some
constraints that we can apply
to the model in some scenarios.
But in general, safety
is an open-world problem.
You need to handle all
sorts of different ways
in which your model could
do something that's unsafe.
And arguably, large-scale
machine learning
has been the most
successful way to handle
open-world circumstances.
And so as a result of this,
it seems like perhaps we
should try to collect
large amounts of data
that would teach our model what
is safe and what is unsafe.
Now, at the same time, this
is really unsatisfying.
This means that we actually have
to somehow collect a lot of data
under unsafe circumstances.
And it also can have some really
real and negative ramifications.
So as an example,
there was news articles
that talked about how tech
companies are basically
trying to do content
moderation or label data that
is traumatic or toxic.
And labeling that
kind of data can even
cause humans all sorts of
mental health challenges
and has a lot of
ethical considerations.
And so this approach isn't
satisfying for handling
this sort of safety
critical problem.
And so can we
develop methods that
can learn what's unsafe
without expansive data,
without expansive
human labeling,
data of incidents
that happen themselves?
Maybe we could use
synthetic data for this.
Maybe we can use some
sort of prior knowledge.
This is an open
challenge and would
have a lot of benefits in terms
of the safety of these systems
and the safety of
training these systems.
And then separate from that,
as these models are improving,
we also want them to remain safe
during the exploration process
and during the learning process.
And this is something
that humans are actually
pretty good at doing.
And as a silly example,
maybe a couple years ago,
I taught myself how to ride
my bike without holding on
to the handlebars.
And I did so without
ever falling off my bike.
And I'm not saying that to brag.
It's not that hard.
It took time, took effort.
But I think it's really
fascinating to think about
how would you get a robot
to, for example, learn
how to do a new behavior like
that without ever falling
or without ever causing
damage to themselves.
And it means that
you're fundamentally
exploring a new part
of the state space
while also understanding what
might be more risky and less
risky and thinking about
a curriculum over how
to accomplish that
sort of objective.
So separate from safety,
although related,
is that these models do, even in
non-safety critical scenarios,
make mistakes.
Sometimes, these mistakes
are called hallucinations.
Probably, many of
you have encountered
these kinds of mistakes before.
I'll provide one
example here, where
I was asking it to tell me
what the weight of the sugar
on the bowl is in this image.
And it confidently told me that
the digital scale on the image
reads 108.2 grams.
That is the weight of the
sugar currently in the bowl.
This answer is incorrect.
It's actually a bit different
from what the scale shows,
although it's also
very challenging
to read what the
scale shows because
of the glare in the image.
And oftentimes, in
language models,
humans are the recipient of the
predictions of these models.
And this means that
oftentimes mistakes
are fairly manageable because a
human can discern whether or not
the model was saying the right
thing or the wrong thing.
But the interface between
these humans and these models
is not well optimized.
And as an example of this,
there were multiple studies
that have looked at how AI
systems work with doctors.
And in one study,
it found that when
the AI was working
independently,
it was able to
achieve 92% accuracy.
When physicians were
using AI assistants,
they only had 76% accuracy.
And that was barely better than
when humans were acting alone,
which was 74% accuracy.
And it seems like for these
systems to be more effective,
we should take into account
the fact that they'll
be working with humans with
actually making decisions
at the end of the day.
Like, 92 sounds
great compared to 74.
But if it is going
to be a system that's
interacting with a person, 76
doesn't sound quite so great.
So can we optimize for
better human AI systems?
And as part of this, maybe
one way to achieve this
was if models could better
estimate uncertainty and better
estimate when they
might be giving
the right answer
versus when they might
be giving the wrong answer.
And there's research that shows
that if you take a pre-trained
model and plot the confidence
of the model versus the accuracy
of the model--
so the confidence is the
predicted probability
of the answer that
it gives- and this
is the actual accuracy of
those answers on average,
you see that it's actually
very well calibrated.
So that confidence actually
reflects its accuracy
really well.
But then after post-training
with reinforcement learning,
we actually see that the model
becomes far less calibrated.
And so maybe
reinforcement learning,
while it's making
the model better,
is actually deteriorating
some of the calibration
that these models might
have at the beginning.
Perhaps one direction,
there was some research
by Tian et al. that showed that
if you verbalize the probability
rather than using the
probability like the logits
in the model and encourage it
to provide multiple guesses,
then you can get more calibrated
model performance after RLHF
compared to the RLHF model.
So maybe that's one
possible direction.
Even then, you
need to figure out
how this would
interface with a human
and then evaluate how it does
when the human and model are
working together.
But yeah, this is, I think,
an important open problem
for thinking about
how humans and AI
systems are working together.
And then even separate from
that, a lot of AI systems
are not going to have a human
there at the end of the day that
are checking all the answers.
And this is true in
autonomous driving,
where a human isn't going to
be always holding the steering
wheel.
This is true in
robotics, where maybe you
will be working with a human.
But probably, many
of the decisions
won't be checked by a human
compared to many of the language
model use cases.
And even in language models,
there's lots of use cases
where you want to just plug
that in to another system
to control some system.
Maybe web agents, for example,
will be autonomously choosing
what to do.
And so in those scenarios, can
we get really high reliability?
Reinforcement learning is
likely a part of the solution.
Online data is really helpful
for getting high performance.
And there's promising results
that reinforcement learning can
give really high reliability.
One example by Luo et al.
showed that on fairly
challenging robot tasks,
they're able to get performance
where they ran the policy 100
times and it worked 100 times.
So that's pretty cool.
But extending this to
large-scale scenarios
where you need to have
really high reliability
is quite important.
And then the last thing I'll
talk about is evaluation.
So in supervised learning,
we can measure accuracy.
And we can use held
out validation sets.
And this is kind of
like heaven because we
can get a very nice
measure offline
of how good our model is.
But in reinforcement
learning in general,
there aren't any
reliable offline metrics.
And to evaluate
performance, typically,
at the end of the day, you
just need to run your policy,
roll it out in whatever
environment you're in,
and measure the reward or
measure the performance.
And the reason for this is that
this data collected so far,
under whatever policy, differs
from the data that was collected
by the learned policy.
And so it's really hard to
evaluate the policy on states
that the policy
is going to visit
when you don't have
those set of states
that the policy will
necessarily visit.
Now, to make matters worse, if
we have a generalized system
that is intended not just to do
one task but to do many tasks,
then we need to
evaluate our policy
not just in one circumstance but
in all sorts of circumstances.
And this means that
we need to collect
large amounts of online
data and evaluate all
of those different rollouts.
And this makes it really
hard to decide first
if the policy is good enough
to deploy or even just
the simpler problem of picking
which of your different models
is the best model and choosing
hyperparameters, for example.
As a real-world circumstance
of this problem,
about a month ago,
OpenAI released
a ChatGPT model, a new
version of GPT-4o, I think.
And if you asked
it, how many people
am I better than at thinking?
it said, if I had to
put a number on it,
I'd estimate that you're
easily in the 130 to 145
range of IQ, which would put
you above about 98% to 99.7%
of people in raw
thinking ability.
But honestly, comparing
you to most people
almost insults the quality of
mind you're aiming to develop.
So maybe this isn't what you're
kind of expecting or looking
for in your model.
And OpenAI actually
ended up needing
to rollback this update that
made the bot excessively
flattering to users.
This gets at the
challenge of it's
really hard to know if the model
that you're developing is good
enough, is better than your
previous model, and so forth.
It's really hard to
evaluate these systems.
A couple specific
open questions.
First, can we develop
offline metrics that
can at least rule
out bad models,
let alone estimate performance?
Estimating performance
would be the dream.
But at the very least, maybe
we could rule out models
that we shouldn't
deploy offline.
And then even in terms of
online policy evaluation,
if we need to evaluate a policy
in all sorts of circumstances,
can we figure out how best to
select representative scenarios
that will allow us
to measure generalist
performance without
having to evaluate
every single possible scenario?
Now, that was all I had for
frontiers and open problems.
And I guess one thing
I want to convey
is that now that
you've taken the class,
you should be really
well equipped to start
tackling these challenges.
You don't know everything
about reinforcement learning,
of course.
But you should know a lot
of the fundamentals that
will allow you to go
read research papers,
understand where the
state of the art is,
and build on the
state of the art.
So your question is, why
does this happen basically?
So I don't think we
necessarily expect this.
But looking at
this in retrospect,
I think it's reasonable to
make some guesses for why
this is happening.
And I think the predominant
theory for why this is happening
is that the objective that
you're optimizing for, first,
is not exactly accuracy.
It's not exactly
aligned with that.
And typically,
what reinforcement
learning with human feedback--
what it's doing oftentimes
is actually sharpening
the distribution.
So the pre-trained
model, it often
will output all sorts of stuff.
And what RL is trying
to do is-- let's
say this is the mode that
we really want our model
to be predicting.
And it's to be sharpening
that distribution
to really encourage the model
to be more likely to sample one
mode.
And that sharpening
often leads to it
being overconfident in certain
circumstances, especially
when preferences are rewarding
you for being confident
and then also, at times
being correct and confident
and sometimes being
incorrect and confident.
So let's talk a little bit
about how to do research.
And this will be a focus on
how to do research that's
more of an empirical flavor
similar to the research
that you do if you were doing
a deep reinforcement learning
project.
Now, before we get
started, I have
a couple different thoughts.
The first is that
I'll talk a lot
about how I go about the
research process and advice
that I give to PhD
students as I see
them working through
various research projects.
But there's many different
ways to do research.
And it's important and
good for the community
to do research in
many different ways
because that leads to
more diverse discoveries.
And if everyone did research the
exact way that I do research,
then we would probably have
fewer diverse discoveries.
And so diversity is good.
And my research approach is not
necessarily the best approach.
And I don't think there's
any one approach that
is the best approach.
I also felt like it
could be good to give
a little bit of a backstory,
which is that I did not intend
to have a career in research.
I was planning to go to
industry and develop products,
which is what my parents did
in various engineering fields.
And I felt like that was the
way to have real-world impact.
I did internships in industry
and eventually figured out
that I was excited about AI.
And I was excited about
algorithm development.
And it seemed like the
frontier of that and algorithm
development was really
in a research environment
rather than in an
industry environment.
And a lot of the topics
I was excited about
didn't really work.
Things like robotics
Even today, robots often
don't work very well.
And so they're really in
this sort of research domain.
Also, the people that
I met in industry
that were working on
the kinds of things
that I wanted to be
working on all had PhDs.
And so I was like, well, I
should probably get a PhD too
if I want to work
on those things.
And then I also just found
research and the ambiguity
of research to be really
kind of intellectually
interesting and challenging.
And so that's all
to say that you
don't have to intend to
have to work in research
in order to eventually
end up doing research.
And then the last
thing I'll mention
before getting into
how to do research
is just like some general
realities with research.
The first is that very, very
few research ideas are good.
And very, very
few research ideas
have impact, have lasting
impact especially.
A lot of ideas don't work.
A lot of ideas don't
work to the extent
that they won't lead to papers.
As an example of this,
here are the outcomes
of some of my research ideas.
And here are the outcome of
some more of my research ideas.
And there's a lot of failure.
And the risk and the
challenge of doing research
informs different ways--
a lot of what I'll say
has to do with dealing
with that sort of risk and
dealing with those challenges.
And then even if it does lead
to a paper, a lot of papers
won't necessarily
have a lasting impact.
The second thing
that I'll mention
is that research is
inherently incremental.
We are building upon the
knowledge of previous research
that's been done.
And as an example
of this, AlphaFold,
arguably like a really impactful
thing, very, very successful,
arguably could be
considered a breakthrough.
This itself was, in
many ways, incremental.
It built very closely on a large
20-year academic project called
CASP, which was a protein
structure prediction project
that was basically kind of
a competition and a data set
for doing this sort of structure
prediction and also built very
heavily on advances
in neural networks.
And so even if any one research
project isn't a breakthrough,
it often plays an important role
because it allows other projects
to build on it or other projects
to potentially rule out ideas
that have been tried already.
And then the last
thing that I'll mention
is that oftentimes people
think about developing
really cool, fancy algorithms.
But in a world where scaling
up is often quite important,
especially in AI
research, oftentimes
it's actually the
simple ideas that
have more impact than the fancy
ideas or the complex algorithms.
And that's just because the
simple ideas are the things that
can scale, that
are the things that
are easy to be integrated
into different systems,
and easy to build on top of.
With that out of
the way, I'll talk
about what to work on,
how to do the work,
how to share the work, and then
a couple miscellaneous topics.
And I would argue that
these three things--
picking problems to work
on, doing the research,
and sharing the work--
are all equally important.
And it's easy to think that
maybe number 2 is the most
important or maybe number 1.
But all of these are actually
really, really important
for being successful
in research.
So step 1 for what to work on--
I think that a research
project needs two things.
The first is an
important problem.
And the second is a plan for
how to approach that problem.
And if you only have
one of these, then
usually that doesn't constitute
a good project direction.
So for example, maybe
one project idea
is I want to solve
climate change.
That is an important problem.
But I don't have a plan
for how to approach it.
So it doesn't make a
good research project
even though it's a
really important problem.
Second, maybe I have a
really cool algorithm
that at best will make a robot
or a reinforcement learning
system a little bit
more successful.
This is maybe a
really cool idea.
And maybe I have a plan.
Maybe I have two.
But I'm missing the
important problem
that this is actually solving.
And so for this
latter part, I think
it's really important
to think about,
if the project is really,
really successful,
what will the outcome look like?
Does it solve an
important problem?
Or what is the upper
bound of that project?
And if the upper bound
is not very high, then
usually it doesn't make
for a very good project.
Step 2, if you have an
important problem and a plan
for how to approach it,
are you excited about it?
Research is a lot of work.
And if it's fun, if you think
it's really cool and exciting,
then you're more likely
to work hard on it.
And if you're
working hard on it,
you're much more likely
to be successful on it.
And this is actually probably
true for a lot of things
outside of research too.
It's good to spend
time on the things
that you find exciting,
that you find really cool.
Probably, if you can find
some of those things--
they may not even
be just one thing.
If you can just find
something that you think
is really cool
and exciting, then
you'll probably do
a lot better at it.
And then step 3, like I
mentioned before, a lot of ideas
don't work.
And so it's really
good to think about,
if you are brutally honest
about why your idea could fail
to solve the problem,
does the idea still
have a good chance of working?
And if not, then
probably it won't work.
And that's mostly just because
of the reality of most ideas
not actually
working in research.
And it's important to
be honest with yourself
about whether this will actually
solve the problem or not.
So that's my three-step
process for picking problems.
Now, a couple more
thoughts on this.
So research can often either
start with an idea or a problem.
And I think both of these sorts
of approaches to a project
have merits.
And I've done research
that's more idea-driven.
I've also done research
that's more h driven.
But I tend to lean
towards one myself.
And the reason is as follows.
So if you start
with an idea, you
need to find a problem
that that idea solves.
And there may not exist
an important problem
that the idea solves.
It may solve a problem.
But there might be a better
way to solve the problem.
And if there's a better
way to solve the problem,
then that idea may not
have a lot of impact.
On the contrary, if you
start with a problem,
then you're trying to find the
best solution to that problem.
And one downside is it may
be harder to write a paper
if the solution ends up being
kind of obvious in retrospect.
But at least you're
guaranteed to be working
on an important problem.
And you find a solution.
You'll still be happy
even if it ends up
being a little bit
harder to figure out
how to write a paper about it.
Another way to put this is
that with idea-driven research,
your goal is to get
the idea to work.
Whereas in the second case, your
goal is to solve the problem.
And the second camp seems like
a much more comfortable place
to be because it's
possible that the idea just
doesn't want to work.
Or it's not going to work
at the end of the day.
Another note here is that if
you're thinking about a problem
that you want to solve,
it's really important
to get to the bottleneck
of that problem.
So if the problem is
bottlenecked on data,
for example, and
you start exploring
new algorithms separate from
the data for how to solve it,
then you actually probably
won't see performance gains
from working on methods if
it's bottlenecked by data.
And most, maybe you'll
see a couple percentage
points because, really, the
big performance gains are
going to be on the data side.
And so if you pick
the things that
are bottlenecks and the things
that are actually preventing
that thing from
working, then you're
more likely to be
able to make progress.
And so I think a lot of
problem-driven research
ends up thinking about what
is the bottleneck for solving
this problem.
And this can also be even
in terms of much longer term
thinking.
You can think about, I want to
develop an LLM that can solve--
it can prove something that
humans have never proved before,
like P versus NP or something.
Or I want to get a robot that
can make a bowl of cereal
in a new kitchen.
Those are things that you can't
solve in any individual research
project.
But you can think
about, OK, what's
the bottleneck
for getting there?
And can I work on the
part of that problem
in my next project
that will make progress
on that larger goal?
A couple more things.
For this next thing, I want to
tell a little bit of a story.
So in the second year of my
PhD, I did an internship.
And I did an
internship at Google
where they had all these robots.
And I wanted to use the
robots to do something cool.
And my project idea was to
build a predictive model,
actually a video
generation model,
and use it to learn
skills across the robots.
And then there was a problem.
Most research projects have
problems that you find.
And in particular, I discovered
that video generation models
were really bad.
So here was a video that
I collected on the robot.
And here was a prediction from
arguably the state of the art
video generation model.
And you can see
that it is erasing
all the objects in the video
and is barely capturing
the motion of the arm.
Doesn't even capture the
background correctly.
And so this means that I
wasn't able to actually use
these kinds of models to
actually get the robot
to do something better.
Now, at the time, I
kind of viewed myself
as a machine learning and
robotics person and not really
a computer vision
person, not a person
who works on generative models.
If I kind of felt like I should
only work on machine learning
and robotics, I might have
to table this and figure out
a different project to work on.
But instead, I decided to work
on trying to develop a better
video generation model.
Now, arguably, I
wasn't necessarily
the best person to do this.
I had never built a
generative model before.
I didn't really
know that much about
architectures for doing so.
But not a lot of people
were working on it
at the time because
they didn't realize
how bad these models were.
And then the resulting paper
ended up being the basis
for work in my job talk, now
has around 1,300 citations.
And it arguably
informed the community
that it's kind of an
interesting problem to study
and led to much better video
generation models than the one
that I was able to develop.
And so I guess
the kind of lesson
that I'm trying
to convey here is
that it's good to not box
yourself into an area and say,
I'm only going to work
on this particular area.
And the reason for that is if
you cross topic boundaries,
it's going to
inform new problems.
Because if you're
trying to use something
that is a problem for advancing
the topic you want to work on,
then that kind of
informs that there's
a problem with that
existing thing.
And oftentimes,
people in that field
don't know that it's a problem.
And then it also
brings new ideas
to that other topic
or domain as well.
And so I see a lot of people
kind of boxing themselves
into areas.
But I think that actually
crossing topic boundaries
ends up leading to a lot of
new insights and innovations.
And then the last
thing that I'll mention
is don't be a perfectionist.
So I've seen people feel
like they want to pick
the perfect project to work on.
But you never know what
the impact of a project
will be at the outset.
Otherwise, it
wouldn't be research.
And so at some point,
you need to just start
trying different ideas, start
getting going on a project
without trying to find
the perfect project.
So once you have a project
idea or a project direction,
a key consideration from
there is handling risk.
So we've talked about how lots
of research ideas don't work.
How do we deal with that?
So there's a lot of tricks
for dealing with the risk.
And not all of them are going to
apply to every single project.
But these are
tricks that I think
you should be able to draw upon
to handle the risk in research.
So the first is,
wherever possible,
it's good to front load
the risk in the project.
Think about, what is the reason
why this might not succeed?
And before developing
infrastructure,
before coding up the entire
algorithm and so forth,
if you can formulate and
run simple experiments that
test the core unknowns
that you have,
then you can bring the risk to
the beginning of the project.
And this can be
really uncomfortable.
Because oftentimes, building
the infrastructure, coding
the algorithm, whatever,
that's like the easy part.
That's the part where you can
seemingly make some progress
on the project.
But if you do all that
and then, at the end,
realize that the core
unknown actually ended
up not working out, then you
wasted all of that time--
even though it seemingly
seemed like progress,
you wasted all that
time on that idea
that wasn't going to pan
out at the end of the day.
And so instead, if you
can frontload that risk
and frontload the
unknowns, run experiments
to test those unknowns, then
you can make sure that--
if this is applicable,
you can do that first
and then build out
the infrastructure
or build out the
algorithm completely
and run all the experiments
after doing that initial test.
Along the same lines,
thinking through how
to test ideas in the simplest
possible way or the fastest
possible way takes some skill
and takes some thinking.
It's often not obvious how to
test a particular hypothesis.
So separate from trying to
frontload risk and frontload
experiments is simply
just iterating a lot.
So you have to get lucky to
stumble upon a good idea.
But you can create
luck for yourself
just by trying
out lots of ideas,
by iterating on lots
of different ideas.
And if you try out an idea and
the targeted experiment doesn't
work, then you can
discard it quickly,
try out another
idea, and so forth.
And for me, there was kind
of lots of times in my PhD
where I tried out lots of ideas
that didn't make it into papers.
They failed.
And I think that this allowed
me to come upon some ideas that
worked well.
I didn't always do this.
Sometimes, I ended up banging
my head against the wall
plenty of times.
But this is something
that I found
to be a good strategy for
trying to iterate and get
through the bad ideas
quickly so that you
can get to some good ideas.
And then I think the
last thing on this slide
is if you can try out
lots of ideas, especially
at the beginning
of the project, you
can try out lots of
ideas at the beginning
and then not commit
to any one of them
until you see some signs of
life on that core unknown.
And then if you find signs of
life on one of those projects,
then you can start to
commit to that project
after you see some sort
of initial result on it.
So this is another
brute force approach
to trying lots of
different things
so that you can get
through the bad ideas.
So the question is, in
problem-driven research,
it's a bit more
comfortable because you
can try out multiple ideas.
Are there scenarios where there
isn't like a ton of ideas?
And yeah, there's
definitely scenarios
like that where you
may not have tons
of ideas for solving a problem.
And I should mention that in
this approach, where you try out
lots of different
things, you could also
be trying out multiple
different problems as well.
And so yeah, you
could be trying out
like a couple ideas
for one problem,
try out a couple ideas
for a different problem,
and then pick your problem based
on what seems to be tractable.
Because even at the outset,
you don't know how hard
a problem is going to be.
And it might be that it's
too hard for the scope
of a current project.
Or we don't have good tools or
good ideas for how to solve it.
Can I give an example of
frontloading a core unknown
in a project?
A couple ideas.
So maybe I'll try to
give a couple examples.
So one example is I worked
on meta learning in the past.
And the goal was to
see if you can quickly
adapt with a very small
amount of data to a problem.
And the goal was
ultimately to be
able to get a robot, for
example, to quickly adapt
to a new task.
But actually, designing a meta
learning system on a real robot
is a ton of work and
would take a lot of work
to even just do
the coding for it.
And so what I did is I first
set up an experiment where
the tasks-- instead of
learning robot tasks,
the tasks were regressing to
simple 1D sinusoid curves.
So really, really
simple problem.
And then just tested, can you
learn with a few data points,
like five data points,
to regress to the curve?
And so it was this experiment
that I coded up in a day
and get some initial
results from.
And it ended up working
out pretty well.
And so then that gave me
the signs of life to try it.
Another example of this,
maybe a more recent example,
I've been thinking a
little bit about how
to get robots to follow
different kinds of language
instructions, including
language instructions
for different strategies.
And there's a couple
of risks for this.
One is getting good
labels for the strategies.
And the second is
actually getting the robot
to pay attention to those
different strategies.
And that second
one actually seemed
like the bigger challenge.
And I took a data set where
it was like a really, really
simple problem, where
in some of the data,
the robot used
the right gripper.
And in some of the data, the
robot used the left gripper.
And then I trained
a policy just to see
if it could do that very simple
thing, very easy to evaluate,
and I could
automatically determine
if it was using the right
or left from the data
rather than doing labeling.
And so that kind of isolated
a core risk of the problem
before moving on to the broader
problem of getting a robot
to follow strategies.
Now, you have a problem.
You have an idea.
You want to get things to work.
One thing that's really hard
in terms of getting something
to work is if you're
starting with something
that doesn't work.
So if you coded up a system
and it's not working,
there's a million reasons that
could be why it's not working.
And it's really hard to figure
out which of those things
might be causing it to not work.
You can make visualizations.
There's various tools for
trying to figure that out.
But it's much easier to start
with something that works
and then make it
harder than to start
with something that doesn't
work and try to get it to work.
And so one thing that's
very useful in research
is to-- if you're in a scenario
where things aren't working,
simplify the
problem dramatically
until something does work.
And then move it back
to the harder setting
by, for example, adding more
data, more tasks, whatever.
And yeah, really useful
debugging strategy.
And I've seen, yeah,
a lot of projects
where things aren't working.
And you just kind of need to
go back to the drawing board.
Maybe as a very specific
example for this, at one point,
I was trying to
train robots to be
able to see a video of
a human doing a task
and then do the task themselves
with imitation learning.
Collected a really diverse data
set of robot demonstrations
and then asked a human
to do what the robot did
of all sorts of tasks.
And we just told people
collecting the data,
do whatever you want.
Do lots of things.
Nothing worked when
training on this data.
Spent like months trying
to get the robot to do it.
And then what we did is we
simplified to just a single task
setting.
Like, can we get the
robot to do one task
and make sure our imitation
learning stack works?
It actually didn't work.
And so we had to debug that,
get it to work on one task,
then get it to work
on three tasks,
then get it to work on 10 tasks.
So yeah, starting
with something that
works-- really, really helpful.
Simplifying is really
helpful for that.
Another thing, it's really
easy to get in your own head
and just have trouble debugging
something just by yourself.
And so talking to
friends, colleagues,
advisors can also
be helpful and help
you figure out whether it
makes sense to jump up a level
and reconsider the problem or
keep on tuning hyperparameters
or try something that
you didn't think of.
And then also,
revisiting assumptions.
So you might go into
a project thinking
that something is a lot easier
than it turned out to be.
And then you might learn through
the course of the project
that that thing is
actually really hard.
And so thinking
through, like, has
anything changed about my
assumptions from the beginning?
And then if something
has changed,
would that change
the way that you're
going about the project
or even the project
that you're working
on as a result?
And then maybe I'll also
talk about a story for this.
So there's scenarios
where you're trying
to get something to work.
And it doesn't
really want to work.
It's not really easy
to get it to work.
And if it doesn't really
want to work, then probably
the idea won't be
very impactful.
Because if someone else is
trying to get it to work
and it also doesn't
really work for them,
then maybe the idea just
wasn't really meant to be.
And at one point, we
had this project where--
this is actually a
fairly recent project
where we were trying to
get a robot to follow
open-ended language commands.
Can you clean up the
trash but not the dishes?
We also wanted to see if
the robot could handle
various interventions, like--
and follow lots of different
prompts, for example.
Then we kind of got some
initial signs of life on that.
And we're like, oh,
well, maybe we could also
get the robot to ask questions
if the prompt is ambiguous.
And we had all these
kind of cool ideas
for how we could incorporate the
open-ended language following
in a robot system.
And despite having
positive initial signs
of life, after we
introduced all those ideas,
things weren't really working.
And we kind of tried
all sorts of-- we
spent a couple of months
trying to get it to work.
And at some point,
we kind of went back
and thought about, well,
OK, it was working before.
What parts of this
thing do work?
And what parts of
these things are
harder to work with
our current method?
And then we rescoped the
project to remove the hard parts
that we didn't know
how to solve yet
and to only consider
the kind of interactions
that our method did work with.
And so it was an example
where we scoped the project
to the source of things that
the method wanted to work on,
it worked easily on,
and left the things
that it didn't handle
for future work.
We described it as
limitations in the paper.
And so scoping down
the project, especially
if you scoped it up a
little bit too eagerly,
can also be a useful
strategy in research.
Last thing, if you're in a
scenario where things really
aren't working, you might
decide whether or not
you should pivot
or whether or not
you should start working
on a different project.
Oftentimes, you'll
consider this later
than you should be considering
this because you really
want to get something to work.
There's also this
sunk cost fallacy,
where if you spent a lot
of time on something, then
it's very natural
for humans to think
that you'll spend less
time on it in the future
because you spend a lot
of time on it in the past.
This is a fallacy,
not always true.
And you might actually not
have made as much progress
on the problem than the
time that you spent on
it would suggest.
Now, deciding when to pivot is
really hard because you're often
thinking about,
should I continue
working on my current project?
Or should I switch to
starting a new project?
And this option of
switching to a new project
is really nebulous.
This could mean a lot
of different things.
There's a lot of different
things you might be doing.
And so it's really
hard to think about,
should I be doing what
I'm currently doing?
Or should I do something else?
Because something else
could be anything.
And so one kind of mental
trick for thinking about
this sort of decision
about whether to pivot
is to change this
decision and actually
spend time thinking
about other projects
that you would do and
then try to formulate
the decision as
continuing working
on the current project
versus working on project B
or working on project
C and so forth.
And this decision is much
more concrete, a lot more
straightforward to think about,
less anxiety inducing, and so
forth.
So the question is, when
research fields are moving
really quickly, you might be
worried that another group will
do the same thing and
then try to spend less
time on the evaluation just to
try to get the paper out faster.
Is that a trend?
What do I think about that?
So there's definitely
papers that have spent--
that should be more thorough
with the evaluation.
That's been true.
That's true now.
That's also been
true in the past.
I don't know if it's been
getting worse per se.
I think that if there
is a feeling to do that,
I think you really want to be
confident about the results
that you're putting out.
And I think that if you're
worried about being scooped
or another group
doing something,
there is an advantage to having
done some sort of idea first.
But there's also a lot of
advantage to executing really
well on a project.
And sometimes, the projects
that are executed on better
are more impactful
than the projects
that were like first
at a particular idea.
And so I guess my
perspective is to still put
a fair amount of focus on
execution and evaluation.
Now, there's many things
you could evaluate.
You could run your
experiments on 20 data sets.
And so there's a limit
to what you want to do.
So I think there's a balance.
And certainly, there are some
parts of the research field
that move fast.
One thing that I've
liked about real robots
is that a small enough people
work with like real hardware
that you have to worry-- you
can worry less about that
in many ways, especially
if you execute on it
and actually show the
results on real robots.
But there's a balance.
And it's also good to work on
things like language models
and things that are hot too.
Yeah, there's a balance.
So how to share your research?
I talked about why is
this really important.
So if you think about what
is the output or the outcome
of research, the
output of research
is essentially ideas, knowledge,
things that you learned
from doing the research.
It's not a product.
It's not a service.
It's really knowledge.
It's things that you learn.
And if it were a product,
then the high impact
would mean that lots
of people are using
the product for good things.
But since it's more
like knowledge,
if no one knows about what you
learned, then there was really
no impact or no output as a
result. And even for companies
that have products
and services, they
have massive marketing
efforts to try
to get those products out.
And so for your work to have
impact, you need to share it.
And you need people
to know about it.
Otherwise, it won't
have had impact.
Now, there can be reasons to not
be excited about sharing work.
You can say maybe it
feels like self-promotion.
Maybe the idea didn't
work that well so I'm not
that excited about sharing it.
Maybe it seems all obvious.
All of it seems
obvious to you now.
And so why do you
need to share it?
But even if it feels
like self-promotion,
you're teaching people.
You're sharing
cool new findings.
And you can think about it as
more actually doing a service
to them to teach them something
new and useful and interesting.
Even if it didn't
work that well,
it's really useful to share
because other people might
think of that idea
and might want
to know how well did it work.
And did it work in
certain circumstances
more better than
other circumstances?
And then, yeah, after
enough research,
you're going to know a lot
more than other people.
There will be things that seem
really obvious to you that are
not obvious to other people.
And it's good to still
share those things
and think about what actually
other people don't know
so that you can share
the things that you
have learned, especially
the most important things,
with them.
Now, I could probably
give an entire lecture
on presenting research and
writing and presentations and so
forth.
But yeah, having
really clear writing,
really clear visuals,
really clear presentations.
Communicating clearly is
really, really important.
If they don't understand
what you're saying,
then they won't
understand the knowledge.
It's important to think
about their audience
and how they will interpret
what you say, what they know.
When in doubt, assume
that your audience
knows less rather than more.
This can actually be a
little bit tricky to do.
It's good to avoid
jargon if possible.
They might know the jargon.
But if there's ways
to avoid it, then it
makes it more accessible.
And even if they do
know a lot of what
you're going to
say, a lot of people
still appreciate
refreshers, especially
if those refreshers are clear.
And it might actually cause
them to think about something
that they know in a new way.
Other ways to get
better at this-- just
practicing-- practicing
writing, practicing, giving
presentations.
You can practice alone.
You can practice with other
people if it's a presentation.
And then just try
to get feedback.
Try to get honest
feedback from people
and improve with the feedback.
Now, when trying
to write a paper
or when trying to create
a slide deck or something,
it's easy to get a
little bit overwhelmed
by how much you
have to do and where
even to get started on that.
I find it really helpful
to break down the task.
And even on a pen and paper,
just write down some ideas
for how I want to do it.
Maybe write down an outline.
My recommendation would be
to think through your ideas
for what you want to communicate
before asking your friend,
before asking your
friend ChatGPT.
And then a couple
miscellaneous things.
First is mentorship.
I think mentorship can play
a huge role in research.
And if you have it, don't
be afraid to lean on it.
In my first research
paper in my PhD,
I like hardly wrote
any of the paper.
And I talked to
actually my co-author.
And he told me that he actually
even rewrote the section
that I wrote.
And so it's OK to not
know everything and not
know how to do every part
of the research process.
And lean on other
people for the things
that you don't
know how to do yet.
Generally, I've seen
students and myself
do most successful when
they're learning more gradually
and when they're not trying to
take on everything themselves
because doing novel research
and writing a paper about it
and presenting it-- like,
picking a problem, all of that
is a really, really
huge undertaking.
And it's useful to
lean on other people
as you're trying to
learn how to do that.
And then confidence.
So there's a lot of reasons to
lack confidence in research.
No one knows how to
do research right now.
No one knows what research is
going to be most impactful.
If they did, it
wouldn't be research.
Many ideas don't work.
Many papers get rejected.
Many researchers
have been thinking
about a domain for many years.
And they will be smarter
than you in that domain
because they've been thinking
about it for many years.
And so it's easy to think that
you know very little, that you
have been rejected many times,
that a lot of your ideas
don't work, because all of
those things are kind of true.
But that doesn't mean
that you're actually
doing a bad job at research.
And confidence is
really important.
If you're not
confident, if you're
second guessing,
overthinking things,
it can really slow you down.
And even though these
things are challenging,
they're actually not
reasons to be unconfident.
And then lastly, some
closing thoughts.
Maybe since you're all here,
you're eager to do research.
And so maybe I don't
need to say this.
But in terms of the time
that we're in right now,
I think that you might feel like
reinforcement learning works now
to some extent.
And so maybe we don't
need to do research.
Maybe we can just use
the thing that works
and apply it in all
sorts of circumstances.
And there's a lot of
merit to applying research
in the real world.
It's good for some
people to do that.
But at the same time,
I think that now
is a better time than ever to do
research because we are actually
seeing new research
being translated
into very real-world impact.
And a lot of the
big breakthroughs,
like AlphaFold, like
ChatGPT, and so forth,
compared to the breakthroughs
of like 10 years ago
or 20 years ago,
these are things
that are actually leading
to really massive impact
in the world today.
And if you work on
research now, you
can help contribute to those
kinds of new breakthroughs
that will have even more
impact in the future compared
to if you were doing
research 10 or 20 years ago.
So I think that now is
actually a better time
than ever to be doing research,
including in deep reinforcement
learning.
So yeah, those are
my final thoughts.